《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
嗨 我们好像又迷路了
Hi, we're... We're kind of lost, again.
我们要去指挥中心 你能…
We're trying to get to the CIC. Could you...
别说话
No talking, no talking, please.
别作弊 举高点
No cheating. Hold it up, a little higher.
无耻 8 9…
Sneaky. Eight, nine...
重新开始     你不是认真的吧
Start again. You aren't serious.
零…
Zero...
我想知道为什么赛昂人这么恨我们
I've asked you here to find out why the Cylons hate us so much.
你在卡拉狄加退役仪式上说
It's what you said at the ceremony.
人类是有缺陷的
That humanity was a flawed creation.
人们还在因为一些小事…
And that people still kill one another
而自相残杀
for petty jealousy and greed.
你说人类从来没有自问  为什么有资格生存下去
You said that humanity never asked itself why it deserved to survive.
也许你们没资格
Maybe you don't.
在舰队中潜伏的间谍
Sleeper agents within the Fleet.
被暴力接管
Takeover by brute force.
赛昂人怀孕
Cylon impregnation
和生殖
and reproduction.
各种外形
Multiple models.
自杀炸弹
Suicide bombings.
攻击性
Assault on
与生俱来
natural resources.
盛传卡拉狄加上有一个赛昂人间谍
REPORTER: Speculation continues that Galactica is harboring a Cylon agent.
目击者声称看到一个赛昂人
Eyewitnesses claim to have seen one of the known Cylon models
进出卡拉狄加的监狱
moving in and out of Galactica's brig.
阿达玛上将未对此发表评论
Admiral Adama has made no comment on this situation.
我们将继续
We will continue...
媒体怎么会知道?
How the hell did this get out to the press?
我倒有点奇怪他们现在才知道
ROSLIN: I'm surprised it didn't happen sooner.
我听说你常去见她
I'm told you've been meeting with her regularly,
还允许她和你的船员接触
allowing her to interact with members of your crew.
她有军事价值  提供给我们非常重要的战略情报
She's a military asset providing us with vital strategic intelligence.
让我们祈祷她没有和其它赛昂人串通
While we pray that she's not somehow colluding with other Cylons.
如果我发觉她对这个舰队形成任何威胁
If I felt for one second that she posed some kind of a threat to this Fleet,
我会亲自动手杀了她
I'd pull the trigger on her myself.
我想舰队需要听到你这些话  上将
I think the Fleet may need to hear that, Admiral.
还要让他们相信这些话
Even more, they need to believe it.
你今天怎么了?
Someone took their vitamin this morning.
是啊 我也不知道怎么了
Yeah, I don't know what got into me.
不 你是对的
No, you're right.
让莎伦 沃莱瑞活着  允许她继续怀孕
Keeping Sharon Valerii alive, allowing her pregnancy to continue,
这些都不该发生
there is no road map for any of this.
是应该有人经常问问这些尖锐的问题
Somebody, somebody has got to keep asking the hard questions.
我同意
I agree.
我想预做准备 承认赛昂人的存在
I want to stay ahead of this. Acknowledge the Cylon's existence
然后制定某些规则 以便让她继续留在卡拉狄加上
and then make some kind of case for her to stay aboard Galactica.
我不认为这会有用
I don't think that's going to work.
怎么? 为什么?
What? Why?
我认为你应该相信大家
I think you need to trust the people.
利用新闻媒体 告诉他们真相
Use the press, tell them the truth.
我的意思是  我们对赛昂人所知甚少
I mean, we barely know anything about the Cylons,
在我们得到更多情报之前  我们不会毁掉…
and until we learn more, we're not gonna destroy
我们目前唯一的情报来源
the only source of information that we have. Period.
很好 就这么简单 嗯?
Good. That simple, huh?
哦
Well...
我能走开一会吗?
Could I... Could I have a minute?
当然 很重要?
Sure. Important?
刚才你说要多提尖锐的问题
You were saying about the hard questions.
我知道这个只是我参加辩论赢的戒指
I know it's just my Debate Team ring,
但这是我能找到的最好的
but it's the best I could do.
这本不在我计划之内
This really isn't how I planned it.
不管怎么说
Anyway...
比利
Billy...
我爱你
I love you.
我从第一天见到你就爱上了你
I've loved you since the first day I met you.
你当时半裸着
I mean, you were half-naked, granted.
我知道你没心理准备
I know that I kind of blind-sided you with this, okay?
我并不是说明天马上就要结婚
I mean, it doesn't have to be tomorrow.
我们可以再等等
We can take our time.
比利  我不能嫁给你
Billy, I can't marry you.
我不知道怎么对你说
I don't know how else to say it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他拿出戒指 我就象被电击了一样
He pulled out that ring and it was like an electric shock.
几乎说不出话来
I could barely say anything.
嗯 也许你在后悔没有同意
Well, maybe you're regretting that you didn't say yes.
不
No. No.
我不知道我和比利会怎么样
I don't know what to make of me and Billy,
但是我知道我不能嫁给他
but I know I can't marry him.
但是 我同样不知道你和我会怎么样
Then again, I don't know what to make of you and me, either.
对不起!
Excuse me.
是 对极了
Yeah, sure thing.
嗨 再来两杯
Hey, two more.
马上来
Coming right up.
艾伦
Ellen.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
很高兴见到你  上校
It's good to see you, Captain.
小杜
Dee.
比利
Billy.
我不知道你在这里
Didn't know you were coming down here.
我这两天不当值
I grabbed a two-day rotation.
我就想该休两天假
I thought I'd grab some R and R.
我有公务 和往常一样
I'm on business, as usual.
阿达玛上校
Captain Adama.
我真是个白痴 是吗?
Oh, I really am an idiot, aren't I?
不 比利  别
No, Billy... Don't.
别在费心了   你能走开一下吗?
Don't bother. Can you give us a minute?
不 请坐 上校  别客气
No, you know what? Have a seat, Captain. Be my guest.
比利 对不起
Billy, I'm sorry.
我以为我们会以诚相见
I thought, if anything, we were honest with each other.
你明明知道今天要和他到这里来  你还让我向你求婚
But you knew you were gonna be here with him today, and you let me propose to you
我不是…
I didn't...
我知道给你那个戒指很蠢
I know that giving you the ring was stupid.
那没关系
That's fine.
也许我们的确不适合结婚 但是...
And maybe this wasn't gonna work out between us. But this...
你应该告诉我你和他的事
You should've told me about this.
这很难 你知道吗?
Oh, it's hard, you know,
选择和谁相爱
to choose the people we fall in love with.
一次只爱一个人
To love only one person at a time.
象我们这样的人就更复杂了
People like us are more complicated.
我们?
Us?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我和朋友一起来的
I'm here with friends.
艾伦 你经常来这里 对吗?
Ellen, you're a regular here, right?
你见过那个角落里的女人吗?
You ever see that woman before, in the corner?
哦 就刚才进来的时候见过
No. Only when I came in.
我还在奇怪他们怎么开始穿制服了
And wondered when they were gonna start enforcing a dress code.
艾伦 洗手间在那里
Ellen, the bathroom's over here.
你当真?
Are you serious?
我们走
Let's go.
李 阿达玛 你让我吃惊
Lee Adama, you amaze me.
就现在?        你准备好了吗?
This is it now. You ready?
是的
Yes.
我们听你的
We're with you.
干吧
Do it!
所有人到吧台边上去! 快! 过去!
Everybody by the bar! Now! Move.
你 你 站起来靠着吧台
You, you! Up against the bar!
哦 天啊!
Oh, my Gods!
三男 一女 都有武器
Three men, one woman, all armed.
这是真的吗 舰队的人知道我在卡拉狄加上?
Is it true? The Fleet knows I'm on Galactica?
我感兴趣的是航行可能遇到的风险
I'm interested in navigational weaknesses.
虫洞 黑物质盲点 可能设埋伏的地方
Wormholes, dark matter blind spots. Likely ambushes.
我会躲开脉冲星  因为雷达会受到干扰
I would avoid these pulsar pointers because of dradis interference.
如果我来策划一个伏击  我会放在那里
If I was gonna plan an ambush, I'd do it there.
这要看情况  上将  他们会适应你的行动
It depends, Admiral. They adapt to your every move.
根据你的变化而变化
Every move triggers a countermove.
适应  这就是你们所擅长的 对吗?
Adapt. That's what you're good at, right?
为什么你不回答我的问题?
Why won't you answer my question?
舰队的人知道我在卡拉狄加上吗?
Does the Fleet know I'm on Galactica?
孩子在踢我
It's the baby. She's kicking.
舰队中的确有人知道 今天所有人都会知道
The Fleet knows. That'll be all for today.
卫兵
Guards.
如果人们知道…
You know, if people knew
你这么依赖那个东西的所谓情报
how much you've relied on that thing's so-called intelligence,
他们会吓得半死
they'd be scared out of their wits.
你呢  少?  你怕她吗?
What about you, Saul? Are you afraid of her?
知道吗  实际上我不喜欢他们和我们这么象
You know, the truth is I don't like the way it's gotten under your skin.
你想干吗?
What are you doing?
压力舱会在爆炸时开门减压
The pressure hatch can withstand explosive decompression.
现在进来的唯一方法就是里面发生强烈爆炸
The only way help's getting in is with a raft of high explosives.
或者我们可以让这些小丑自己打开压力门
Or we could just let these clowns open the pressure door for us.
安全部队肯定会马上赶到了
There's bound to be a security force on its way soon.
为什么他们会自己打开门?
Open the door for us? Why would they do that?
把杯子给我
Give me your drink.
让我和他们谈谈
Let me talk to them.
干冰 我需要干冰
The ice. I need the dry ice.
好了 保持冷静
Okay, stay calm.
艾伦!
Ellen!
请别开枪
ELLEN: Please don't shoot!
你是谁?
Who are you?
艾伦 泰
Ellen Tigh.
过来 马上
VINSON: Get over here now. Move!
我们不是罪犯  我们是舰队的一员 和你们一样
We are not criminals. We are members of the Fleet, just like you.
我丈夫是卡拉狄加的副长
My husband's XO of Galactica.
你们已经犯了一生中最大的错误
You've just made the worst mistakes of your life.
泰上校 上将 你们该听听这个
Colonel Tigh, Admiral, you need to hear this.
少
ELLEN: Saul.
艾伦? 怎么了?
Ellen. What's wrong?
他们抓我们作人质
They're holding us hostage.
他们威胁要杀我们
They're threatening to kill us!
我叫萨莎 阿比诺尔
My name is Sesha Abinell.
我控制了星云九号的休息室
I have seized control of the Cloud 9 lounge
这里的人都成为人质
and held the people in it hostage.
你想干吗?
What do you want?
我想干吗?
What do I want?
这并不是我想干什么的问题
This is not about what I want.
舰队已经变成了赛昂人的地盘
The Colonial Fleet has become a Cylon-occupied territory.
阿达玛上将  你正在和那个…
You are working in collusion with a Cylon agent.
企图在你的船上谋杀你的…
The very same model of the Cylon
赛昂人的同一型号密谋
that tried to murder you, Admiral Adama, on your own ship.
我们要莎伦 沃莱瑞
We want Sharon Valerii.
给你两个小时
You have two hours.
把萨莎 阿比诺尔所有资料给我
Get me everything you can on Sesha Abinell.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
萨莎 阿比诺尔
GAETA: Sesha Abinell.
是雷 阿比诺尔的遗孀
Fleet records indicate she's the widow of a Ray Abinell.
雷 阿比诺尔在大约10周前
He was a casualty aboard the Greenleaf freighter
赛昂人攻击格林里夫号运输船时阵亡
when the Cylons hit it about 10 weeks ago.
寡妇
Widow.
我们还有谁在星云九号上?
Who do we have aboard Cloud 9?
嗯  换班计划上说阿达玛上校  一半的陆战队
Rotation schedule shows Captain Adama, half a Marine squad,
还有星芭儿也在那里度假
and Starbuck's already there on R and R.
马上找到星芭儿
Get me Starbuck right away.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
你们之中肯定有一个氧气传感器
Hell, one of you beauties has got to be an O2 sensor.
我猜就是你
And I'm guessing it's you.
吸点二氧化碳吧
Take a sip of carbon dioxide.
还有一个人在里面
There was another guy at the bar.
检查一下后面 不要再出任何错
Check the back. We don't want any more mistakes.
柯恩 这里有很多军队的人
Kern, there's an awful lot of military types here.
所以我们选择这里 以引起卡拉狄加的注意 记得吗?
And that's why we're here. To get Galactica's attention, remember?
佩奇 你去
Page, you go.
没问题
No problem.
很高兴见到你 盖尼
Good to see you, Gunny.
我正需要一些陆战队员
I'm gonna need some of those gorillas you call Marines.
我的人大部分都在这儿了 长官
Most of my gorillas are already here, sir.
正打算度个小小的假期
Just trying to cop a little R and R.
说说情况
STARBUCK: Tell me about it.
嗯 我们知道的情况如下
All right, here's what we know.
有几名持枪者挟持了至少20名人质
We got an unknown number of shooters, at least 20 hostages,
在他们开始杀人质之前 我们还有大约90分钟
and about a 90-minute window before they start throwing out bodies.
你有计划吗 长官?
You got a plan, sir?
把枪上膛 其余走着瞧
Lock and load. Let's figure out the rest as we go along.
放下你的武器
Put your weapon down!
告诉他们
Tell them.
他说他是卡拉狄加的阿达玛上校  他说他只想谈谈
He says he's Captain Adama from the Galactica. He just wants to talk.
谈谈 就是这样  只是谈谈
Talk, that's it. Just talk.
他们是一起的
SESHA: They're together.
放下枪 否则要她的命
Put it down or she dies.
嗨 她死 他就死 懂了吗?
Hey! She dies, he dies. You get it?
区别在于 你不会开枪 他会
The difference is, you won't do it. He will.
好吧
Okay?
我们都有自己关心的人
We all have someone we care about.
这是他儿子
It's his son.
他不会为了赛昂人不要儿子的
He's not gonna choose the Cylon over his son.
和别的人站到一起去
VINSON: Get in line with the others.
二氧化碳浓度增加
The CO2 is through the roof.
他们想让我们窒息
They're trying to suffocate us.
这是什么意思 陷阱?
What is this, a trap?
在船上不能乱开枪是有道理的
There's a reason you don't just start shooting on a spaceship.
你们可能打到了什么管线  为什么不让我和上将谈谈
You probably nicked a line. Why don't you let me talk to the Admiral,
看看有什么办法可以解决
see if we can't find a way out of this?
我派两个攻击小队过来协助你 10分钟内到
I've got two strike teams inbound to you. ETA ten minutes.
我们会有足够的火力 那很好
We'll have plenty of firepower, so that's good,
但是我担心无法接近
but I'm concerned with limited access points.
上将 是阿比诺尔
Admiral, it's Abinell.
让星芭儿随时和我们保持联系
ADAMA: Keep Starbuck on the line with us.
阿达玛
Adama.
我们的氧气正在流失
We're losing oxygen.
如果不能修复 人质就会死
If it's not restored, the hostages die.
那你们都会死  这就是我的回答
Then you all die, because this is over.
我不会死在那个赛昂人前面
Not till the Cylon's dead.
我就是死也要看着她先死
I'm willing to die to see this through.
你想拿你儿子的命来冒险吗?
Are you willing to risk your son's life?
婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
你终于肯听了
Suddenly, you're listening.
天杀的  给她想要的  把赛昂人给她
Gods damn it! Give her what she wants! Give her the Cylon!
由你决定  上将
You're all alone on this, Admiral.
她有军事价值 我不会把她给你用来复仇的
I'm not gonna sacrifice a military asset on your altar of revenge.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
这…
This isn't...
你说你这么干是因为赛昂人欺骗我们
You said this was about us being played by the Cylons,
但并非如此  你这么干是因为你失去了你的丈夫 我很理解
but it isn't. It's about the loss of your husband, and I understand that.
你只是想报复 我也理解
It about you wanting to strike back, and I understand that, too.
但是我们都失去过我们关心的人 我们要学着接受
But we've all lost people that we care about, and we learn to live with it.
上将 我想你肯定知道  根据确凿证据
I am sure you are aware, Admiral, of the concrete evidence
卡布里卡的防御系统就是被一个
that Caprica's defenses were compromised by a Cylon agent
渗透入国防部的赛昂人间谍在进攻前夜破的
who infiltrated the Ministry of Defense on the eve of the attacks.
当可怕的事发生后 人们总是去寻找一些复杂的理由
People look for complicated answers when something terrible happens.
也许我们只是因为受到突袭 所以战败了
Maybe we were just caught by surprise and were beaten,
也许我们应该学着接受这个现实
and maybe we have to learn to live with that.
也许你还没搞明白
And maybe you are just missing the point.
你们当时被渗透了  你 军队
You were infiltrated. You, the military.
现在你们又被渗透了
And you are being infiltrated again, right now.
你可以坐在那里假装知道自己在干什么 但你不知道
You can sit there and pretend you know what you're doing, but you do not.
你被欺骗了
You are being played.
我们其他人不想和你的船一起去死
And the rest of us do not want to go down with your ship.
马上派人来修好供气系统
I want this air system restored right now.
只允许来一个人 修完后离开
One person comes in alone, fixes it, leaves.
出任何差错 就有人会受到伤害  这都要算到你头上
Anything goes wrong, somebody gets hurt, it's on your head.
保持和星云九号的直接通信
Keep a direct line open to Cloud 9.
我们怎么办?
What do we do?
我们去修理供气系统
We repair the air system.
少  我们不能把莎伦交给她
Saul, we can't give her Sharon.
我希望你能理解这点 好吗?
I hope you know that, right?
我理解
I know that.
我们不能和恐怖分子妥协
We can't start dealing with the terrorists.
我们一旦开了这个口子 就会没完没了
We start now, it'll open the floodgates, and it'll never stop.
但是 它不是莎伦
But, by the way, it's not Sharon.
它他妈的是个赛昂人
It's a frakking Cylon.
你以为我不知道?
You don't think I know that?
我发现有时候你看着那个东西的眼睛
I think there's part of you that looks into that thing's eyes
依然把它当作两年前的
and still sees that young girl that reported aboard
那个来报道的小女孩
two years ago as a rook pilot.
它不是她
Well, it's not. It never was.
比尔 它是个机器
Bill, it's a machine.
上将  是特蕾丝上校
Admiral, it's Captain Thrace.
报告情况
Sitrep.
我让一个星云九号的技术人员
STARBUCK: I had one of the Cloud 9 techs
检查了两次氧气供应
double-check the oxygen feed in there.
供气系统没有任何问题
There's nothing wrong with the air.
可能是个小故障
ADAMA: Could be a glitch.
或者有人对里面的二氧化碳传感器动了手脚
Or maybe someone screwed with one of the CO2 sensors in the bar.
李 为什么?
Lee? Why?
也许他给了我们一个进去的机会
Maybe he's given us an opening.
如果我能派个人进去 就能搞清楚里面的情况
If I can get someone inside, get a clear idea of what we're dealing with...
卡拉 这是个侦查任务 找个志愿者
Kara, this is a recon mission. Get someone to volunteer.
然后你评估一下情况
Then you assess the situation,
然后行动 明白了吗?
and then get the hell out of there. Do you understand?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我来修氧气管
I'm here to repair the O2 line.
上校 你干吗?
Captain, what are you doing?
做志愿者 让我看看这个
Volunteering. Let me see that.
关上舱门  搜她身
SESHA: Close the hatch. Search her.
你不该关上门  你们快没氧气了
You may not want to do that. You're running out of air in here.
没带武器
Looks clean.
干活吧
Do your job.
看好她
Cover her.
等一下  慢慢转过来
VINSON: Wait a minute. Turn around, slowly.
重新检查一下那个盒子
Check the box again.
行动 快
MARINE: We're hot! Let's go! Hurry!
蹲下
Get down! Get down!
我们立刻出去 快
We gotta get out now! Come on!
比利 比利
DUALLA: Billy, Billy.
我需要衬衫 毛巾 任何可以当绷带的东西
I need shirts, towels, anything I can use as a bandage.
比利!
Billy!
没人允许你动
VINSON: Nobody said you could move.
你们还想要那个赛昂人吗? 想吗?
You still want the Cylon? Do you?
如果上将的儿子死了你们什么也别想得到
Because if the Admiral's son dies, you're not gonna get a deal.
明白吗
You get that?
如果他死了 你们就得不到你们想要的
If he dies, you're not gonna get what you want.
他是对的 让他去吧
He's right. Let him go.
长官 是星芭儿
Sir, it's Starbuck.
我们得到报告 发生枪战  怎么回事?
We got a report of gunshots. What's happening?
我被他们识破了  不得不行动  对不起
My cover was blown. I had to move. I'm sorry.
有伤亡吗?
ADAMA: Any casualties?
两个陆战队员可能在行动中被打死
Two Marines, probably KIA,
至少一个歹徒
at least one of the gunmen,
还有李
and Lee.
里面太混乱了 他被打中了
It was crazy in there, confused, and he got hit.
严重吗?
How bad?
我不知道
I don't know.
原地待命
Stand by.
没我的命令不要行动
Hold your position. Make no move unless you hear from me.
是自己人打的
It was friendly fire.
李被自己人打中了
Lee got hit by friendly fire.
我想是我打中了他
I think it was me.
照我的命令做
You have your orders.
我止不住他的血
DUALLA: I can't stop the bleeding.
我能帮你吗?         我止不住他的血
What can I do? I can't stop the bleeding.
我要止住血
I gotta stop the bleeding.
不知道是不是打中了动脉
I can't tell if it hit an artery.
李 别离开我
Lee, don't leave me.
李 别离开我 好吗
Lee. Lee, don't leave me, okay?
求你了
Please.
嗨
Hey.
他会没事的 他会没事的
He's gonna be okay. He's gonna be okay.
他会没事的 只要按住 来吧
He's gonna be okay. Just hang in there. Come on.
别离开我 李 别离开
Stay with me. Stay with me, Lee. Stay with me.
你是在欺骗我们吗?  你是在欺骗我吗?
Are you playing with us? Are you playing with me?
我救过这船  救过你
I've saved the ship, saved you,
有多少次?
how many times now?
五次? 六次?
Five? Six?
你们还是不相信我并没有什么阴谋
You just can't believe I'm not playing against you.
你知道舰队里还有赛昂人
You know that there are Cylons within this Fleet.
你知道他们长什么样 你知道哪里能找到他们
You know what they look like. You know where to find them.
如果我问你 你会告诉我他们是谁吗?
If I were to ask you, would you tell me who they are?
不
No.
我相信你不会说
That I believe.
他会没事的
He'll be all right.
谢谢关心
Thanks for the concern.
她失去了一个丈夫  突然间这个世界好像欠了她什么似的
She loses a husband and suddenly the world owes her an explanation.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
他不但是她丈夫 也是我兄弟
And he wasn't just her husband. He was my brother.
我兄弟死在了派亢  他也是个好人
My brother died on Picon. He was a good man, too.
他们都是好人
They're all good men.
那个叫阿比诺尔的女人在占领酒吧前
The Abinell woman sent over a manifesto to the press
给新闻媒体发了个声明
before they took over the bar.
基本上都是些关于赛昂人...
It's mostly a collection of rumor and conspiracy theories
在军队和政府里的谣言和阴谋理论
about Cylons in the military and the government.
都是扯淡
Bunch of crap.
这些消息挺受关注  我们要赶快把 我们的人救出来
It's getting a lot of attention. We gotta get our people out of there.
你有陆战队在星云九号上
You have Marines on Cloud 9.
入口的压力门又关掉了
The pressure door to the room has been resealed.
如果我们要炸开它 需要很多G4炸掉
If we try blowing it open, we'll need so much G4
还要冒把里面所有人炸死的风险
we'd risk killing everyone inside.
我们已经没有选择余地了  只有一个办法
There are no options left except for one.
不 我们不能和恐怖分子妥协
No. We don't strike deals with terrorists. We can't.
莎伦不能交给他们 否则…
We give them Sharon Valerii, we're inviting terrorism,
我们的权威性会受到质疑
and we weaken our position permanently. You know that.
先生们 在那个房间里的每个人
Gentlemen, everyone in that room
都是某人的儿子 某人的妻子 某人的母亲
is someone's son, someone's wife, someone's mother.
比利是我在这个世界上留下的最接近亲人的人
Billy is the closest thing that I have to family left in this world.
如果你们认为这对我的情绪没影响
And if you don't think that that confuses things emotionally for me...
那你们就错了
Let's not be naive.
如果他们是对的呢?
What if they're right?
如果莎伦是真的一直在欺骗我们
What if Sharon has been playing us all,
一步步把我们引向毁灭呢?
plotting our destruction with every passing day?
如果恐怖分子是对的呢?
What if the terrorists are right?
这和莎伦没关系 这比那个重要的多
This isn't about Sharon. It's about something much bigger than that.
这关系到我们的长期生存
It's about the long-term survival.
这关系到我们在处理这些事的时候如何控制自己
It's about the way we conduct ourselves in all of this.
长官?  阿比诺尔要和你通话
Sir, it's Abinell on the line.
我儿子怎么样?
How's my son?
还活着 但我的朋友却死了
Alive, but my friend is dead.
还有你的两个士兵  不过你儿子快要死了
So are two of your soldiers. And your son's dying.
知道吗 这件事我想了很久
You know, I thought a long time about this.
关于我该怎么做 关于我会做到什么程度
About what I'd do. About how far I'd go.
直到现在我才想明白
And I honestly did not know until this moment...
两
Two.
怎么?  怎么?
What? What?
站起来
Get on your feet.
你想干什么?
What are you going to do?
少 给他们想要的!
Saul! Give them what they want!
它不过是个机器!
It's just a machine!
哦 不 不
WOMAN: Oh, no. Oh, no. No!
他们会杀了她
They're gonna kill her.
别开枪
Hold your fire.
我会把赛昂人交给你
I'm giving you the Cylon,
但她不会是活的
but she won't be alive.
这是什么意思?  我的条件可不是这样的
What does that mean? That is not the deal.
你已经说服了我 也许我们的确被欺骗了
It means that you've convinced me that we may have been played.
如果真的是这样 如果她一直在欺骗我
And if that be the case, and she's been playing with me,
那么我不能再让她活着
then I can't take any more chances. So you make up your mind.
所以你来决定 你想要莎伦 沃莱瑞 可以给你
If you want Sharon Valerii, you can have her,
但要按照我的条件
but on my terms.
我给你她的尸体  你给我人质
I give you the body, you give me the hostages.
同意
Done.
挂断
Cut the wire.
很好
It's good.
安全
Coast looks clear.
上将 让我帮你 求你了
Admiral. Let me help, please.
让我来吧
Let me take it from here.
我们走
Let's go.
别再看着他了  比利
DUALLA: Stop looking at him, Billy.
我能看出来你盯着他  我知道你认为你可以抢到那把枪
I can see you watching him. I know you think you can get that gun.
我只是在想 万一发生了什么事
I'm only thinking in case something happens.
不 你不是战士
No. You're not a soldier.
你没受过训练  你不用去证明些什么
You're not trained for that. You've got nothing to prove.
我知道
I know.
他们就在外面 我们开门 他们会给我们尸体
They're right outside. We open up, they'll give us the body.
好吧
Okay.
我们这就开门
VINSON: We're opening the door.
但是出现任何差错 我们就会杀人质
But if anything goes wrong, we start killing hostages.
打开
Do it.
结束了
It's over.
等等
Wait.
好像不对头
This isn't right.
这个已经死了几周了
This one's been dead for weeks.
他们的赛昂人还活着
Their Cylon is still alive.
杀掉他女朋友
Kill the girlfriend.
死了  报告你们的情况
Down! Report!
我们控制住局面了
MARINE 2: We're contained!
安全
All clear!
安全了 抓紧
All right, we're all clear. Grab this tight!
这里需要帮助
DUALLA: I need help over here!
带急救队来
MARINE 3: Bring in the ER team.
医生 快来
MARINE 2: Medic, get in here now! Medic!
房间远侧 就在那边
Far side of the room. Right over there.
李 能听到吗? 李!
Lee. Lee, can you hear me? Lee!
血压    好了
MEDIC 1: Blood pressure. MEDIC 2: Right.
能听到我说话吗 李 振作 儿子 振作起来
Can you hear me, Lee? Come on, Son. Come on, hurry up!
血压很低
MEDIC 1: BP's weak and threading.
好
That's good.
比利
Billy. Billy.
Billy.
比利
这就是你给他们的?
ROSLIN: Is this what you gave them?
这是计划内风险
It was a calculated risk.
为个赛昂人不值得
It wasn't worth it.
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
这样好多了 好多了
There, that's better. That's better.
他还这么年轻
He was so young.
嗨
DUALLA: Hey.
Hey.
怎么了?
What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
等你好些了我们再谈
When you're feeling better, we can talk.
真是个该死的假期
It was a hell of a vacation.
是啊
Yeah.
李?
Lee?
李 你不能死
Lee, you can't leave.
你必须活下来
You have to stay.
你必须活下来 知道吗?
You have to really stay. You understand?
没关系
It's okay.
我会在这里等你醒过来
I'll be here when you wake up.
我会等在这里
I'll be right here.